OOP all right recording excellent hey
everybody so Chris and I had the egg we
wanted to make a video and just respond
to the comments from the video that we
did I think it was last last week and I
mean for me one of the I've been so so I
feel so blessed and just to be a part of
whatever this is it we're part of we're
still figuring this out but um but I've
been so grateful for all the way the
ways of participation in the in this
conversation as expressed through the
comments it's also been a place a little
bit of a dilemma for me because I want
to respond to every one of them but I am
NOT a good typer it takes me a long time
to type small right and it and so
there's a it's been a something that's
been kind of wiggling in me of wanting
to respond to everybody but trying to
figure out how to do that in a way that
kind of
should I get to everything else in my
life as well so my thought was as like
Chris Wahab we just make a video and we
just go through each one of the comments
and like we can just respond to them and
however way that we find ourselves
responding to them as a as a way of
possibly including everyone into the
dialogue and let and letting you know
that you're having an impact on on the
dialogue and an appreciation for that
and and a response cuz there's so many
like I've been so impressed with the
thoughts that have come come in the
comments section I'm just like whoa that
I didn't even think this particular
angle or this train of thought it's just
like so it's actually for YouTube having
that having that the tone of the
conversation be so warm
right like it just people's comments be
like assuming positive intention like a
assuming goodwill like a genuine arrest
city like I've that's I know YouTube is
not known for their their generous
manatee and their in the comment section
so remotely no to have that happen and
to not have it be polemical to have it
be really good natured and in good faith
is a novelty a novelty to be grateful
for and then around that novelty I think
they're trying to find a sense of
etiquette it's that's new
so I mean established you can't have an
established etiquette with a new
phenomenon right so then this I think
for maybe what this is in part is trying
to renegotiate a new etiquette for a new
phenomenon because III go that guy I see
some of the comments on any number of
these videos are enough to warrant their
own dialogues just some of the single
comments you know to say nothing of the
long conversations are enough to warrant
their own dialogues and then it's
difficult to know how to respond because
you want to be consistent and you want
to be you want to honor the
participation and dignify it properly so
anyway it's tricky so I think this was
an excellent idea this is a really
really good experimental exercise yeah
totally so let's give it a shot so my
thought is look Laura I'll just read
along and it will read a comment and it
will comment on it and just kind of see
see where we go from there okay we can
get people all right so the first one
from NIC and I'll go ahead and attempt
to read the read it
NIC states the only talk about it made
me realize the ways and the wins I
experienced the world it's it's the
numinous it's the numinous my
grandfather's house is it that can be a
vow it demands respect
I don't experience it as a now facing me
but more a presence of something greater
who
so this is really synchronistic for me
because so thank you for that
thank you for that comment Nick and if
the reason that synchronous
synchronistic for me is that my my
grandmother recently she's she's in her
mid to late 80s but but thank goodness
she's still strong as a bull and she's
just recently sold her house that she
shared with my grandfather for many many
many years and moved into an apartment
completely self-sufficiently and
independent and left to her own devices
and that house my grandmother's house
has also been avowed to me for as long
as I can remember and the feeling of
character and I'm deliberately gesturing
back to our conversation and our
discussion of characterization a little
bit but the character that that house
had over and above any particular person
or inhabitant in it signified in a way
that seemed irreducible to me and also
seemed untransferable and so when she
sold her house even though logistically
it was exactly the right thing for her
to do and I was happy for her it was the
right move it was like it was of her own
volition like everything about it was as
right as it could ever hope for for for
somebody that you love you know for them
to make a decision that's a joyful
decision of their own volition and and
and of sound mind and body and all of
those things were true so there was no
reason to be mournful except for
attachment to that house and so I
remember going one last time to the
house and sort of saying my goodbyes to
it you know it was always wafting with
like the most glorious aromas to because
it was always cooking and like lying
everywhere it was great it was just
there was a wonderful place to be and
and then just recently in November I
went to visit her for the first time
since she moved into her new apartment
and I'd seen the apartment in bare
already so I knew where it is I knew
where it was and I knew what it looked
like bear i knew the size and the shape
and the orientation and all of that but
i was a bit trepidatious but doing it
because i thought well this is the first
time that i'm going to be visiting my
grandmother not in that house and there
was something there was something very
melancholic to me about that and so I
walk in to this much smaller apartment
and lo and behold it's the house hmm
everything had been arranged and
configured in likeness to the house and
that doesn't mean that everything was
necessarily in the same place because it
can't because the dimensions of the
spacer work considerably smaller but
somehow the character of the house was
simply reproduced in a different space
and I was astonished I was astonished at
how how seamless the transition was I
was astonished that it was the same
place wasn't the same space but it was
the same place the logos of the
apartment was the same logos as the
house I can put it that way
it was cohered in the same manner it was
inflicted with the same voice it was her
just as the house had been and I felt as
embraced by it it was as vow to me as
the house had been simply in miniature
and that was a very profound experience
for me too to see that such a thing was
really possible yes anyway sorry that
was that was a bit rambling of me but I
couldn't help but to identify with with
what you said there Nick I thought
that's a cool little synchronicity from
me yeah I think the thing I really
highlighted there for me is like we said
it's numinous right and that yeah that
scent what I take in it mr. B is when
when I when what salient is so well
beyond what I can actually visually see
your taste object somehow reveals the
ah stable right in it it's tone us in
its particularity right when it emanates
like that right in it I'll remember when
I went back to Hinsdale one time I mean
I in my early early years and I so I was
I spent most of the time in downtown
Hinsdale when I was you know basically
four through maybe eight or something
like that and it was kind of right
around the time where I was not learning
how to read and when I got back there
and I was sitting at a for I think like
a like a family reunion or something
like that and I just I was sitting on
the corner of a Starbucks and drinking
coffee and I I looked up at the sign and
and the sign had been there since I was
a kid and I looked up at it and I just I
saw it and it was this this orange this
is like a you know a very simple like
outline drawing flat you know a flat
image and the shape coming in and this
thing kind of eating the shape and then
I just and then all of a sudden I looked
and it switched I realized oh no that's
an eagle going through a movie and I was
like it I'm not cool and I looked up and
then all of these all of the things that
were left when I was a kid almost what
pop pop they popped right and I because
I just saw them obituaries I did when I
was a kid and it's it because the way I
would see it kid it's kind of like it's
hard to describe but I always saw that
thing I just was kind of this monster
thing they kind of went like this it was
unquestioned by me because they didn't
see but then it switched and I was able
to see that and it just went the whole
neighborhood what did you do
there's something about I think
primordial sense ray of the downest of
the world something that like is
so native soil to us like the world is a
whoo right and yeah they also really
like with what you said here Nick about
the mountain can be a vow that demands
respect and especially the sense of
respect of when you think about you know
the word respect spectacle right respect
VC right to real don't think that
commands my respect is something that I
want to keep looking at right there's
something about it that's more than just
one glance beams my respect and the I
don't experience it he says I don't
experience it as it now facing me but a
presence of something greater holding me
thing it's like it's that you right it's
not not necessarily like a face taught
in a conversation but it's some other
now relationship it is something like a
holding it's cradling it's a cradling I
there's even a quote I think I can't
remember whose is it Ponte or her Cyril
but one of them said that something like
that the world is our birthplace because
we are cradled by it but our but but we
our minds are also cradle for the world
right there's a mutual cradling and
that's that that's very very much what
it makes me think of yeah also also Nick
Nick it created a video of our first our
first four-way conversation it was
really great it was a model oh right
that Evo
okay it's really appreciated like the
ideas that he had especially one that
really stuck with me that was when he
said it seemed like the virtue what you
were all doing was lifting each other up
right like that was the virtue so like
the like each play off each other and
the job was like we were we wouldn't go
up until everyone went up like and so
that when you got to the top by virtue
of being at the top meant everyone was
looking top
in distinguishing that part of it that
in here I thought was really beautiful
yet really true in a lot of ways
absolutely it felt that way it's certain
that that's exactly as it felt I'll have
to take a look at that thank you may be
I'd be delighted to read the next one
guy guy is an under racer this is Nick
Nick Shelburne different Nick guy is an
underrated part of the conversation I
rate him very very highly so I don't
know if he's underrated in my books III
rate him that the tip top he speaks with
a certain clarity and deep
self-awareness that helps direct and
frame each conversation ways that were
previously missing I couldn't have said
it better here here that's all I have to
say to that here here and and I'll say
that having that experience I mean right
now even though we just started
recording guy and I are just coming off
with about two hours of just chatting
openly about all kinds of things and
even outside the formality of any
philosophical topic that is that is true
of you guy as an interlocutor in every
moment of a conversation no matter what
it happens to be about and it's a it's a
it's a very privileged position to be
opposite you in a conversation so that
is that comment is excellence very very
true yeah thank you thank you for saying
that
it's funny I actually don't feel like I
don't have the experience of being
underrated I actually am having the
experience of finding more out about
actually I've been doing for years
different context with people with like
the vernacular to talk about four
dimensions of it I think I've talked
about this before where I'm discovering
what I bring to the conversations were
conversing through everybody else so
there's a way in which I'm kind of
finding out it wasn't like I was going
into this thinking but I'm through
hearing from you through hearing from
John the impact of this I'm in some way
catching a glimpse at something I've
been doing for years that's
through the impact that it's making and
it's feeding back it's a it's it's a
it's a really cool it's a very cool
process hmm it's really cool process
alright so the next one okay so good der
a pulled how do you say his last name I
think it's a pulled I pulled yes not
sure all right if we got that wrong
there is a German philosopher who works
whose works might interest you
Hermann Schmitz he does quote new
phenomenology and contemplates
intensively on things like the
inexhaustible object atmospheres and so
forth
I'd map is writing very inspiring
readings
I haven't yet taken a look at Hermann
Schmidt's but but I intend to I'd like
to because that sounds very apropos the
the term atmospheres makes me think of
another thinker whose name is Paulo
Costa it's paolo who talks very much
about that with reference to meaning
with experience of meaningfulness not
semantic meaning but meaning in the
sense of significance in life that we've
been talking about and that and that
John talks about in his videos that he
talks about as sort of a bubble like
there's something atmospheric about the
way we experience meaning that it
prevails upon us it prevails upon our
interaction in that higher order or
superordinate way just as an atmosphere
seems to prevail upon our interactions
physically and that ties in very very
aptly with all like the abundance of
metaphors and analogies that have to do
with with meaning as a respiration you
know an aspiration and inspiration right
all of these variants of the respiratory
metaphors that we tend to use I know I
use them a lot John uses them a lot
we've used them together guy
all of that actually it's a it's an
excellent pairing thinking about
especially thinking about the burgers
notion of the idea of a sacred canopy if
you can start pairing a few things
together you come up with a sort of
cosmological metaphor that ends up being
very powerful oh the idea that we end
well a sacred canopy that encloses an
atmosphere of meaningfulness and then
our relationship to the atmosphere of
meaningfulness is a kind of respiratory
relationship and that connotes the
reciprocity that we often reference but
it also connotes the the the the the the
experience of the experience of
asphyxiation that we associate with
meaninglessness and nihilism and despair
right trying to catch a breath and being
unable or having an abundance of it and
feeling flesh and feeling you know a
feeling inspired so these these
metaphors sort of collage together in a
way that I think is very helpful I can't
with anything else with reference to the
philosopher I'm not sure of yet but
atmosphere is that's what it for me it
picks up on yeah up so looking look yeah
I look I mean just phenomenal just the
whole project phenomenology do you think
about it I just I don't think I seen
anything I don't like about it you want
to read Jake yes Jake eats pizza rolls
great name the way guy talks about
reading books and going on if he doesn't
understand a word and trying to press
the character or vibe of the text is
very much how I listen to these
conversations with Chris John Jordan and
guy and also include in that Jonathan
page oh like a lot of times other Johnny
V I love that can I just say I love that
people are now calling John Johnny V
it's fantastic we'll use very technical
terms that I can't exactly follow I
think that's a common experience or
arpeggio very symbolic language etc but
I find myself letting go of that and
really trying to feel the content of the
conversation the way described in this
video I've often worried that I wasn't
getting the proper meaning from things
because of this but hearing you guys
also think and understanding that way is
very reassuring keep up the great work
you're changing the game thank you for
that thank you for that and yeah it
really is true it's certainly true for
me that that's very very much the way I
also read and listen certain things if I
think that that a certain term might be
really focal for an argument or an idea
that maybe I'll dwell on it for a moment
but generally the the poetic flow of a
conversation or an argument will
intimate its significance more than the
individual instances of semantic content
in any given sentence or phrase and so
following the cadence and the flow of
that that over signified
meaning I find is much more predictive
of the significance and ultimate
direction of the conversation then then
stopping to preoccupy with with any one
phrase or term you know with some
exceptions but I generally find that to
be true and that sense of holding
something that is you don't quite get
but there's a context that is revealing
it and holding that kind of the
ambivalence of understanding around it
and that concept comes up again in
another yes yes
around it you circle around it I think
is there's something very tied I think
to how we acquire language right because
because if you look at if you look at it
epistemologically
how the hell does the chat learn its
first word without knowing other words
by which to work understand that word
there's a mimicry like something much
deeper than epistemology it's like it's
ontological so kind of I think there's
that sense of where a lot of the things
that we're talking about presupposes
that you understand what we're like what
we're talking about in order to talk
about it yeah so complex
right then either they linger as like a
in some ways in some ways I don't even
think I think holds true of like I'm not
even aware that I don't understand it
until I understand it and that it pops
out but that and to just you have a
sense your interest is drawn to
something that you can't quite just know
what is it you're interested in but but
there's something you're connected to
there's some kind there's something that
you can hear the call of what's that
beyond the horizon is having you walk
forward
there's something about a conversation
that seems very very apropos to that
kind of harm you netic phenomenological
unfolding right that's right I'm excited
about the form of the conversations and
like why comments are so cool because
you can kind of get this sense of just
like a lot of these comments you can
feel people having gone through
something like expressing something that
is alive for them they're not just
putting out propositions but they're
disclosing that's right there's no
wonder that the phenomenologist that
list certainly at least like punty were
also taken I mean in some way simply
because they were contemporaneous but
we're taken with with trying to
understand structuralism and trying to
understand the semiotic enterprise
because the tension between the
semantics of the conversation and the
pragmatics of the conversation becomes a
very very pivotal thing right and in
some ways what I'm hearing is that the
pragmatics of the conversation the prime
attak contextualizing of the
conversation is sometimes in the flow of
one course meaning one run through a
dialogue sufficient as a way of divining
its significance and then by repeating
the cycle whether you're actually
repeating reading a book or repeating
listening to a dialogue the semantics
and the pragmatic ways of signifying the
well ways of signifying period
the conversation then begin to there the
relationship between those two
dimensions of signification begins to
come clear it begins to actually you can
negotiate it as you go along so there's
there's an interesting there's an
interesting sort of gesture of faith
implicit in the pedagogical exercise of
simply surrendering yourself to the flow
and then being willing to repeat it so
that those dimensions of signification
can actually work themselves through the
repeat visitation you know and it's like
that sense of like not because it a lot
a lot of conversations is a backdrop of
D besting ourselves from like a like
just you know centuries of Cartesian
presuppositions about things right this
kind of sense of that like what happens
just like outside of the periphery that
you don't notice is as much part of an
influential of the thing that you're
looking at right in that moment so
there's something about all of that that
gets into this kind of thing that that
the Gunter is talking about I think yeah
yeah and and you know that I also have
this sense sometimes in the throw is
even of a conversation or even listening
to one where I I experience the meanings
that erupt from the conversations I
almost sometimes experience them in a
more eidetic way than a linguistic way
right that the content the way that they
the way that they intimate and connote
let's say a particular argument or a
particular phrase sometimes they're they
conjure that there's an imaginal life to
them they conjure images as opposed to
squarely semantic propositions and so
there's something like there's a man I
don't and I don't mm-hmm if this it gets
tricky now right we're in or to a level
of abstraction that becomes tricky but I
don't mean I don't mean image it
necessarily in the literal sense but
certainly the non linguistic sense of
meaning that is intimated by something
that has value beyond its propositional
content and so the rhythms of a
conversation are composed of those more
eidetic entities just as the tone ox the
tone of a conversation is as is as
signifying as its as its content to so
there are all these things that are
going on outside the margins of the
linguistic content that become available
to us when we take a participatory
position with reference to it right then
the conflict day rights that the
conforming logos of participation allows
us I think to to immerse into those non
linguistic properties that begin to
spill out put of the deal logos when
it's when it's committed and when it's
intimate and I think the the the the
possibility that perhaps those who
aren't actually those who aren't
actually partaking of the dialog in an
in the immediate instance of it still
are able to participate around it and
still identify with its process I think
is there's something about that that
lies at the heart of what of the
potential of this enterprise in the
first place which is I think what we're
trying to get at right the participatory
the participatory spirit that confers
itself upon the knowers that know
through the dialogue even when they're
not directly involved at the outset
Chris yeah no I would she hi how are you
it's very nice to meet you I've heard so
many wonderful things about you even
just this evening
oh that was fantastic okay so the next
person Richard Elliot is nothing the
second
thank you guys this is the first time I
felt like I got a handle on the yeah
yeah no kidding me to context of the
conversations I've heard on YouTube
around 35 minutes he spoke of altering
perspectives on objects at Grandma's
plummet make a adult three-dimensional
perspective basically eyes perspective
to an object
he personalized one and trying to hold
that as long as you could that seemed to
me the beginning of trying to adopt a
phenomenological intention interesting
although while being pre verbal I don't
think it sounded pre reflective I felt I
understood how you characterize the
minds facial recognition function that
reflects the relevance RNR mechanism I
think that means relevance relevation
yes precognitive or maybe pre reflective
you know it's interesting I noticed I
noticed um I think I used maybe I used
unknowingly pre reflective in it I've
noticed that I like John's kind of like
like restated some of the things that
I've said whenever I say reflective but
I think I think I do mean that sense of
not just like consciously understood but
yet deeply intelligent right that
primordial ground right yep you realize
and trans frame
I really could see this is like I mean
these are just amazing comments right
yeah yeah I think the world presents
information about itself to us in ways
that are pre cognitive or pre reflective
yeah I I I have known people who are
sensitive to the feel of a room or place
they have never been to and know
something or something terrible has
they've been there places do have aura
okay I said these institutions are not
usually personified from what I have
observed some category mistake I don't
know and I don't usually hang around to
find out I I really sympathize with what
I heard as your question and concern
concerning the integrity of the
particular I believe in personhood
because I believe in the imago in my
good a image of God against teen and I
get to the meta ordinate category of
personhood by chasing down and providing
a taxonomy of psychological qualities
that ranged the broadest scale of the
superordinate to subordinate why nope
not going of why do we have to take
everything to the nth degree
Heidegger wrote of our Comment or
commitments to both the categories we
were given in her culture at birth and
the ones we develop in her projects this
net this necessitates a recognition of
limitation it ain't necessary to know
everything about something it's
impossible the world doesn't still that
hmm I like that I think that's a good
turn of phrase but that says it well to
me any particular object person event
etc should hold the integrity
its uniqueness until it doesn't anymore
relevance redfish um I dated a girl for
a month or so liked her
wanted to get to know her better one day
she says Richard I want to get to know
the real you hmm that was the end I
realize he wanted to me out I felt like
I was about to be sent to dam to file
classified well I'm I'm a free man I
[Laughter]
don't know how to explain personhood I
feel I know how to do it and good luck
to fellows on this project of bowing the
world left of the category you can
personifying being don't mean it that we
will that we will say about this one
I don't know I'm I mean I'm appreciating
the I'm appreciating it appreciating it
yeah I I think without what I'll say is
like I'm first of all I just really dig
intentions that you're making and also
the sense of dudes like it's no complex
there's some things that you just can't
grasp onto and hold in front of you in
fact and I preach I really appreciate
that and I think if Heidegger deeply
appreciates then almost change the world
through appreciating this this sense of
that truth is as much about concealment
as unconcealed mmm there's a way and
really in that word reveal right because
something that sailed right it's it it
connotates preciousness
right otherwise it wouldn't be baled
though to reals really interesting
because to revealed simultaneously means
to unveil but also reveal the it gets at
that sense that you can't ever get Toby
yeah right and some sense right
there's always element concealment to it
and then I see sensibility that I'm
appreciating here in this comment is is
that you can in some way you can attune
to the concealment and actually attune
to concealment and have it be present to
it and be be constituted by it in a way
that doesn't rob it right of it's fun
concealment right just one of the things
Paulo tree and really do work and make
present be be unknown without making it
known right that's exactly that's a very
very I think about what that takes that
takes it all the stuff that that you
know that's right that's exactly what
poetry does um it's it's the nishitani
when he's talking about I the I now
relationship talked about poetry as a as
a spiritual divertissement you know like
an interlude of dance like it's it's a
it's a revelry it's the realization of a
radical realism and finding yourself in
stride with that radical realism in
which you have to cast off your smaller
self your lesser self and then enter or
espouse yourself in greater being right
the self the self that the self that
that the self that 'end Wells the mode
of greater being right in out ahead of
you but that poetry somehow activates
that or activates your rapport with that
in some ways right I was I was thinking
aside from the fact that it's just well
humored quip about that
that that relationship I was thinking as
you were talking about concealment and
unconcealed Matt guy the the idea that
because it sounds like the experience
that that that richard has had here is
that someone tried to try to solve him
like a riddle or perhaps and you know to
do to demystify him and that's an
interesting thing because we I mean we
try and do that to one another fairly
often we try and solve or resolve one
another's though we posed as riddles and
and and to demystify and and and the
process of coming and to know someone is
not I think a demystification certainly
not a comprehensive demystification
because once you feel that you've some
suddenly exhausted somebody you
immediately cease to be interested in
them immediately right once you think
that you have the measure of a person
you have the geometry match exactly I
think most people turn on their heel and
and and they're gone so the unconcealed
meant with the the the the unveiling
with the revealing that you're talking
about that there's something hmm there's
something about well-cultivated
relationships and I mean relationships
in the broadest sense I don't just mean
romantic relationships I mean all all
interpersonal relationships one thing
that they need is I think a way of
ritualizing the process of unconcealed
meant such that it happens at a tempo
with pace with a a with a certain
cadence to allow the unconcealed meant
it's like it's not something that can be
rushed you can't rush to know somebody
because you can't like you can you can
you can strip somebody of their their
their their facticity or factuality
fairly quickly right you can know all
the facts there are to know about
somebody fairly quickly like a few a few
days or
you know a few days is all it would take
to know all of the relevant facts you
will details about a person but of
course as we all know implicitly that's
not particularly revealing out of
context and what the context is is the
shared revealing conformity of a
relationship that then beckons to
something that is that something
combinative between the two people that
then becomes inexhaustible and so the
ritual of unconcealed one another the
ritual of developing intimacy the ritual
of coming to know someone is not a
ritual that we have very well mapped
anymore
even for friendship we don't really have
it very well mapped and perhaps in part
that's because our sociability is no
longer governed by by by by reliable and
observed customs in the way that it once
was and I don't mean to be too romantic
about the past obviously but but there's
something about the hastening to
intimacy that is precisely antithetical
to intimacy intimacy is not something
that you can hasten to knowledge of a
person is not an or gnosis of a person
is not to be more specific is not
something that you can hasten to and I
think in order to make it in order to
cultivate it it has to somehow be
ritualized and I think that's where the
dialogic praxis comes into play the
dialogic praxis is a way of ritualizing
the intimate gnosis of a person and and
and and so the hastening of that process
makes me it makes me think of the Hans
Hans observations about time again right
the whizzing the whizzing the lack of
lingering is something that happens to
sociability just as it happens to any
other kind of exercise and so I
empathized I empathize with this the
frustration of that of being of being of
being treated as sort of something to be
to be to be unboxed God there's this
strange phenomenon with unboxing that's
going on now maybe that has something to
do with it
and because obviously we just don't work
that way I really I just also just
really appreciate when he talked about
and you talked about the beginning to
know somebody and tending to the
relationship that there's a placing
weight to the revealing and in the wreck
like that we used to have rituals like a
courtship the notion of course the
courtship interesting you know in my
lifetime I grew up with this kind of
general sense that I'd lived my life and
somewhere along the way I would meet the
person right that that I would marry in
the living of my life and there was just
kind of the background it was in in in
some way to the fabric of the rituals of
all my social practices in the culture
and all that and very very recently it's
stunning how much of a dramatic changes
is and how no one's have normalized it
got so quickly but it is a dramatic
thing you know this thing is that I
think it's become in the assumptive
background that you probably won't meet
the person that you out in your life
that you're gonna marry you're gonna do
it to a dating website which is when you
think about it that's a completely
different thing
you show up already sizing each other up
right one of the things I've noticed is
that this there's a certain look you
know having your profile I guess is this
whole thing and matching them up and
like looking at the person as a set of
basically quantities right that you show
up already sizing each other up for that
and so you kind of rehearse the person
to this that and the other thing it's
already kind of set up in advance on one
level they're kind of cool about that
right like let's get to it we're just
we're gonna do it the bar any
you're doing that anyway but there's a
way right all of the ride of getting to
know somebody including that withheld
sense of like does she like me do I say
at first or you say first everything
right all of that emerging all of a
sudden boom all that's optimized of you
yes you know I think big last thing he's
in right yes
imagine I could just imagine the
sensibility yes that is probably I could
just see it I don't know if that's like
it seems like the very same sensibility
of how you go about mm-hmm sar
apparently yeah really talking about
that but that's a traumatic change this
is man this is a conversation topic unto
itself that maybe we're gonna have to
have at some point because it's very
very rich and it's bizarre and it's and
I mean one thing that's interesting
about what you're saying I the coming
pre-arranged with a with a with a with
an mo right when you're meeting someone
for the first time versus having to
negotiate it because one thing that's
like something like online dating does
is it pre fits you with context you
arrive you have context context is
important context building cooperatively
developing an unfolding context between
two persons is a is part of the process
of signifying a relationship you signify
a relationship like in any context that
actually is part of developmentally I
think is actually part of the burgeoning
or or or or or sort of like the police's
of a relationship is in part about the
the
the like there's something about the
development of of shared a mutual
condition you know and when you're when
you when you meet someone by coincidence
of your just by by the coincidence of
place you work to negotiate that shared
context and then the content of the
relationship ends up informing and then
interacting with its context as though
between levels levels of signification
when you come pre-fit with the context
there's a certain amount of discovery I
think there's a certain amount of unmute
unconcealed meant and this is not this
is not a this is not a condemnation of
online dating it's just an observation
right that there's actually a privation
of a certain amount of mutual discovery
because part of discovering the content
of one another is described a bring your
mutual context then negotiating it
together and when you come fit with it
now obviously it can change it can
change and it can and it can evolve so
it's not as though I mean you can you're
still going to have to do that but
there's something about arriving and
having it having it premeditated that I
think makes for a very different kind of
experience yeah yeah oh yeah thank you
so much you think about it like in that
slow attacked Minh
closure there's it's funny it's like we
both find out who I am with you through
that act you read the would like a
little bit of like oh man I become
vulnerable and all of that like and so
exactly just like it's me that's gonna
unfold this like one finger at a time
it's more like the act of enrollment in
a sense constitutes of me right is is is
dwells and is of the relationship right
so it's it's like that that sense that
sense of like how relationships
[Music]
it's like yeah there is this quality of
like if we beat and we get into
relationship we spend a lot rest of our
lives together but the self that's in a
relationship with you right will will be
radically the self with the - connected
to the bow of you that constitutes to me
that I don't even know - right on my
thing
great there's like factly yeah you're
right that that's exactly it's a
different Altima one way of putting it
too is it's just a different game you're
playing a different game all of a sudden
right your game isn't to discover what
could be happening your game is now to
figure out what to do about what has
happened thank you so much for this
found myself equaling and recognition um
you know I think I'm so glad that you
but I I i actually kind of i've noticed
this in the like a lot in the comments a
lot and especially the one conversation
we had and i really like this this
experience of where we start talking
about some aspect of life that isn't
total it doesn't quite have a category
right yeah i see something you're like
oh that's right and then all of a sudden
it starts to this this thing that
usually isn't framed start you realize
oh there's a there's something there and
then that starts unfold it felt like a
lot of it understanding right about
everything from learning how to read to
what the experience we were we were
going into a place it doesn't have a
whole lot of language or doesn't it
doesn't show up as a as a something so I
appreciate the giggling of recognition
of that to bring bring to light some
like this experience it's something
that's like so
close in and it's hard to even talk
about it or even than to point at it but
to choose it out right and we're like oh
yeah there is that experience I've never
thought to think about liad there is
it's kind of like this color and it's
like this and and that starts to shape I
felt like that conversation was very
much like that it was really neat oh
yeah yeah yeah I have the same
experience there's so much recollection
that happens because you just well we
before before we started recording we
were talking about this we were talking
about the the the the revelation of what
you already know but weren't aware that
you knew and that process being
analogous invent the very least
analogous to the idea of recollection
and the Platonic sense and so I find a
lot of that that's why there's so much
alacrity in those conversations because
it's like oh my god yes there's there's
just there's it's a cascade of
recollection to me and that's what makes
it such a such a profound experience
giggle yes the Mary Mary this is so
great I have to write this nut down
before it disappears from my head
masculinity and do not read that as men
point well-taken perceives the
vulnerability of the world femininity do
not read that as women is the
vulnerability of the world is the
vulnerability of the world I should have
added emphasis yeah that's
there's a lot going on there I could tip
Polly that's that's very interesting
that's really like almost in every I've
really just appreciated your all of your
comments it's so thoughtful always it
just so I just want to say this I I want
to say that like I really feel genuine
spirits of Christianity and everything
that you do like it's like it's R it's
it's so it's like potent and it's lived
and I can feel you dwelling in it and I
just so appreciate the breadth of your
intellect to be openness of your mind
and like how of of the dialogue is of
the same soil I feel the soil I'm
sitting on is it's as I'm reading and I
feel like the soil is being read that
I'm you know constituted by in some way
so I just really appreciate the wisdom
that you bring with all this is what
this is one of them I'm like oh god yeah
that's so true there is a quality of the
man that like that which can precede the
world right and perhaps this is why this
is why a lot of philosophers right or
like are not a whole lot of women for
the Philosopher's a lot of reasons for
that there is his quality of the
masculine in us he just trip out about
how complex and interesting the world is
like it's almost like that's how we get
pregnant right yeah that's the that's
the police's that's available to us
right yeah he can bird it right and
there is a way where I know this with
them like when I when I talk with my
wife like she I mean she loves the stuff
she's got them wonder bug and stuff but
it's always a sense of like she's so
she's so is the thing I'm talking about
that is it's almost a sense of like yeah
of course it's like that right there's
some kind of innate Ness
right that that in some way is the thing
that I can't stop looking at her about
right well I like she's not as moved to
bring the logos into the introducing
every type thing down to its essential
things so you can experience the release
of the of the break free of the idea
right of the world then all that imagery
that the that you rock forward is just
so luscious and perhaps perhaps guides
because she knows by participation what
you or we struggled to know by
proposition right because when you know
something when you know something by
participation I think that sometimes
your appetite for lending it or loaning
it propositions
is sometimes dulled because they come
they come ready made with insufficiency
right that's why an ineffable experience
is such that oftentimes we're not too
overeager to to to to close it in
language because we know we know that
that all we're going to do is is risk
diminishing it and so to know something
by participation is in some sense to be
sated in a way that we can't be sated if
we're striving to proposition the logos
yeah yeah yeah and then and then I mean
that was obviously the implicit the
implicit eros within the archetypal
structure of that observation then makes
me think of the the ontological flesh
again a little bit right and and and I
think what he describes what Ponte
describes as the reversibility of the
ontological flesh right as a relation
between bodies and that it also makes me
think then about the difference between
dialogue so when one thing that that
some of the phenomenologist stalk about
is the dialogue between subject and
object and and what we've been talking
about all the while is that the dialogo
s-- has a character of gathering
intimacy that is absent
oftentimes in regular discourse regular
dialogue and so it seems to me we were
to be so we've been talking about the D
we've been talking about transmuting the
axis of inter subjective
diello goes to ontological diet to a
dialogic knowing that is not that is
ontological nature right the dying of
the world that's what we started by
talking about and so in some sense I
wonder if the like that the the sort of
that rat that sense of radical realism
in the dialogic process the shared flesh
of logos between between selves is then
a way of almost alkalizing the what or
consummating the flesh between i and the
vow of the world right that the espousal
of shared identity by symbolic
participation we're in sort of the the
flesh the it relation of the subject to
object perceptual dialogue is
recharacterized by the intimating flesh
of the subject to subject the logos
which is thou it has the character of
thou and so then in that exercise that
sort of philosophy of ambiguity resolves
into a like a worldly animation right
everything becomes Rhian chanted like
the anima Mundi right there like the
world the idea of the world soul that it
that the world soul is consummated by
conferring the I thou the inter
subjective the inter social I thou into
our
our relation from a subject object even
down to the way that ancient or
something in the background in the
foreground in a certain way you know
when you bring your attention to some
some part of the world and you give it
like you give it do a tuned attention
and it starts to reveal itself through
the distinctions right in a certain
sense is that kind of erotic
relationship with the world where you
know just like symbolically you know you
could say that you say like the
masculine is something like the the
unchanging forever
open consciousness for which the world
animates right and if that if the
consciousness is dimmed right that the
glow of the world is going to dim it's a
one-to-one relationship so there is this
quality of like thinking about the world
is certain there is a very erotic
relationship to it and I think that's
why distinctions are so especially when
they're first made or they're first
developed right because they have this
process of like you make a distinction
just like when you're drinking wine you
don't know how to drink wine right it
just it's grape juice it burns its
unsweet like why bother
but like somebody really is cultivated
and you start to oh there's a
appreciation the appreciation process
it's very that is a mutual thing where
it's like you make the distinction or
you get the distinction and all of a
sudden there's a difference between the
beginning like of when you're just
smelling it right and the start and the
finish in it once you have those
distinctions and then you can it
literally brings the world into
existence on some level right and
there's a and there's an elation that
comes with that that I think is very
it's about that that thing that that
Mary's getting at right this mm-hmm
this kind of focusing consciousness and
then the world revealing itself you can
feed back on that consciousness
right and inspiring it to go further and
also inspiring her to animate even more
it's such a such a rich it's such a rich
reveal there it is
alright so the next one is I how do you
say that's Diane stay it yeah I think so
Stan Stan yeah thanks again you made me
better understand how I read that was
fun right now there's another one of
those like yeah alright the next one kkb
thank you guy your world and way of
understanding sounds very familiar to me
listening to people in this particular
corner of YouTube is a constant
frustration for me mixed with a huge
challenge of how I can put all to put it
all together in my own way so that it
becomes meaningful for me there is a
great capacity and necessity here for
tolerating the discomfort of vagueness
yeah no kidding and trusting your own
ability that you can resolve the puzzles
somehow through picking up different
signals to the academic for me off
nitpicking semantics that these guys get
so excited about Chris is absolutely
right we brought something different to
this circle a way of orientation that is
alive and grounding here here here here
is the thing I just want to say there is
the that being puzzled and frustrated in
the discomfort of that I think you're
inherently acknowledging this I want to
just I want elucidate that more that
struggle right is we were talking about
this earlier in our conversation
there's ability to grappling with things
that aren't immediately intelligible
mmm-hmm sometimes for a long time right
that is I oh my like so much of what I
call would in my life is about that
sense of dwelling and struggling
something living with it
right and it not being so linear and
that like
Acrobat so you're trying to do in the
frustrations and then the insights and
then they slip away that whole process
of being dwelling in this conversation I
think in some ways is that is the the
point that's the practice point of it
right and it's very it's very it's that
sensibility to well write something that
I think is becoming rare and rare right
there it's such a sense of where if it's
if it's real it's it should be
immediately there right it just kind of
kind of instant optimization the
standing reserve awaiting to be extract
it's it is a resource right all of that
sensibility is so deeply in our all of
our social practices now I think it's
what comes on is going on with what we
were talking about with dating it's so
pervasive and we don't see it and it's
so strange but we don't see it this
sense of like struggling being puzzled
by something like sticking with it like
all of that is like I think to me is a
restoration of something of a deep
wisdom and humility of being with
something and what I didn't like is what
breeds something like character right
mission and like dwelling and something
and reading things and tolerating and
not demanding would be things be
immediately intelligible I think it was
just to practice itself of doing that
whether or not you ever understand what
you were grappling with the process of
attempting to and living with that
process you walk away and you're the
machinery that that exercises right is
in itself in some ways the point or the
benefit right very much absolutely
absolutely absolutely yeah I think this
entire process for me it's simply an
exercise of living within a question and
and you can find your open end itself
within an open-ended
and yeah that's this process to me in a
nutshell
it's it's of course it's uncomfortable
but by by necessity by deep necessity it
is uncomfortable yes how about I'm kind
of I need to go alright should we try
and should we try and do shoe eat should
we just stop and pick it up at another
time or should we just try and plow
through what do you think
okay go ahead guy sing stop you
mentioned that there is a lot of online
comments conversations around the bow
structure of the world inspired I think
by the previous discussion
service-learning John tell me where
those conversations have been taking
place or did you mean the YouTube
comments I'd like to join impossible
things also so I know the book the
second part of the question it was the
book that you actually sent me guy which
I got a lot out of him made great use of
which was Mark I think Rakowski I think
his name is Mark or Kelsey's book on
high degree and Plato I can't remember
the title of it it might just be
Heidegger in Plato or it's something
very straightforward like that anyway
it's a really really good book it it
really is baby we would not have time to
go into it but it's a really excellent
book on hydrous thinking and put those
thinking and where they are concentric
and where they're not and where they're
concentric perhaps even unbeknownst to
Heidegger was thinking was concentric
with Plato's in ways that he may not
have appreciated but but serves to
serves to to inform his own work and
then conversations I don't know of any
other place that that we were
referencing without structure of the
world it's just been out of those
conversations of the four of us and
other one yeah
yeah yeah so how about we just we how
about we pick this up in another video
in a later day okay well maybe we can
like next time we talk we won't talk for
three hours first why not yeah they
caught us they cut us we started
recording when we were already sort of
getting getting towards the university
so yeah maybe well it will inverse the
order next time yeah and just to sneak
preview what what we're talking about
doing is Chris and I are talking about
it a regular you know shoot for like
once a week of starting from the
beginnings of the Socratic dialogues as
spelled out in the original Platonic
Academy apparently there's a way that
they used to have you read the dialogues
yeah I think it's iamblichus is order I
think that's the one yeah so like we we
just had an idea what would it be cool
just to get together and read them and
then talk about them just ongoingly in
that order and and one to discover what
is the intelligibility of that order
which I imagine we'll only know through
the actual enactment of it and then like
Chris and I could be kind of like the
the ones that show up to that every week
but then we can bring other of the
energon and different different people
so kind of join us for who knows how to
unfold I thought it would be just really
an awesome opportunity to you dwell in
that older sense of like of like over
time watching not only under
understanding of the content grow but
like noticing how it impacts who we are
over a period of time and have that all
be reflected in the process I'm excited
to do that do that with I am I'm serious
get up to just you know we can't even
know to what I I think it's it's a
fantastic idea guy of yours and I and I
can't wait to do it it also reminds me a
little bit I was gonna say this to you
earlier it reminds the idea alone
reminds me of something similar to what
Sevilla is doing with Pierre sakes
is doing sort of an ongoing study of zen
motorcycle maintenance
chapter-by-chapter a combination of
reading and annotation she does a
beautiful job of it and and of course
hers it's just her so it's more sort of
mono logic as opposed to we're reading a
dialogic reading of plato's corpus but
but yeah some for a good reference I
think folks who want to if you haven't
already see what she's doing with that
it's really it's fun she does it so well
it's really really it's fascinating text
and the way that she's what she brings
to it is really valuable as well so yeah
I can't wait that'll be fun all right
much love everybody want to stop
recording and